Chuanhao Li

Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia 434-466-6233 cl5ev@virginia.edu https://cyrilli.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am broadly interested in machine learning methods and their applications to information retrieval and data mining. My current research focus is on multi-agent contextual bandit algorithms, with provable performance guarantee under complex environment (e.g., heterogeneity, non-stationarity, and limited communication).

EDUCATION

University of Virginia (UVA), Charlottesville, VA

08/2018 - Present GPA: 3.967/4.0

Ph.D. in Computer Science Advisor: Hongning Wang

Research: multi-agent bandit learning with application to recommender systems

Harbin Institute of Technology (HIT), Harbin, China

08/2016 - 06/2018

M.S. in Mechatronics Engineering Advisor: Gaoliang Peng

GPA: 86.00/100

Research: deep learning methods for vibration signal based machine health monitoring and RGBD image based robot grasp planning

Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, China	08/2012 - 06/2016
B.S. in Mechanical Engineering	GPA: 83.51/100
B A in English	GPA: 92.86/100

Monash University, Melbourne, Australia 03/2015 - 07/2015 GPA: 3.5/4.0 Exchange Student

EXPERIENCE

Department of Computer Science, UVA

08/2018 - Present

Research Assistant

Focus: multi-agent bandit learning with application to recommender systems

Description: I designed and analyzed algorithms for multi-agent bandit learning problems that consider heterogeneous and dynamic user preferences, and communication efficiency under distributed setting.

Mentor: Hongning Wang

Walmart Labs (remotely), Sunnyvale, CA

06/2020 - 08/2020

Research Intern

Focus: online grocery user sequential modeling

Description: I built a self-attention model for personalized next-basket (a set of items) recommendation given a sequence of baskets in user history data.

Mentors: Bo Meng, Peng Yang

School of Mechatronics Engineering, HIT

08/2016 - 06/2018

Research Assistant

Focus: deep learning methods for machine health monitoring

Description: I built convolutional neural network models to predict the health condition and detect possible damage of machines based on vibration signals.

Mentor: Gaoliang Peng

General Motors China Science Lab, Shanghai, China

Research Intern

Focus: road scene segmentation for self-driving cars

Description: I built a deep neural network model for the instance-segmentation of road scene images, i.e., output class, bounding box, and segmentation mask for objects.

Mentors: Xiaowen Dai, Jiangling Du

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] Fan Yao, **Chuanhao Li**, Denis Nekipelov, Hongning Wang, and Haifeng Xu, Learning the Optimal Recommendation from Explorative Users, Thirty-Sixth AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2022.
- [2] Chuanhao Li and Hongning Wang, Asynchronous Upper Confidence Bound Algorithms for Federated Linear Bandits, arXiv preprint arXiv:2110.01463, 2021.
- [3] Huazheng Wang, Haifeng Xu, Chuanhao Li, Zhiyuan Liu, and Hongning Wang, Incentivizing Exploration in Linear Bandits under Information Gap, arXiv preprint arXiv:2104.03860, 2021.
- [4] Chuanhao Li, Qingyun Wu, and Hongning Wang, When and Whom to Collaborate with in a Changing Environment: A Collaborative Dynamic Bandit Solution, in Proceedings of the 44th International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval (SIGIR), 2021.
- [5] Chuanhao Li, Qingyun Wu, and Hongning Wang, Unifying Clustered and Non-stationary Bandits, in International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2021.
- [6] Wei Zhang, Chuanhao Li, Gaoliang Peng, Yuanhang Chen, and Zhujun Zhang, A deep convolutional neural network with new training methods for bearing fault diagnosis under noisy environment and different working load, Mechanical Systems and Signal Processing, 100, 439-453, 2018.
- [7] Yuanhang Chen, Gaoliang Peng, Chaohao Xie, Wei Zhang, Chuanhao Li, and Shaohui Liu, ACDIN: Bridging the gap between artificial and real bearing damages for bearing fault diagnosis, Neurocomputing, 294, 61-71, 2018.
- [8] Chuanhao Li, Wei Zhang, Gaoliang Peng, and Shaohui Liu, Bearing fault diagnosis using fully-connected winner-take-all autoencoder, IEEE Access, 6, 6103-6115, 2017.
- [9] Wei Zhang, Gaoliang Peng, Chuanhao Li, Yuanhang Chen, and Zhujun Zhang, A new deep learning model for fault diagnosis with good anti-noise and domain adaptation ability on raw vibration signals, Sensors, 17, no. 2, 425, 2017.
- [10] Wei Zhang, Gaoliang Peng, and **Chuanhao Li**, Bearings fault diagnosis based on convolutional neural networks with 2-D representation of vibration signals as input, in MATEC web of conferences, 2017.
- [11] Wei Zhang, Gaoliang Peng, and Chuanhao Li, Rolling element bearings fault intelligent diagnosis based on convolutional neural networks using raw sensing signal, in Advances in Intelligent Information Hiding and Multimedia Signal Processing, 2017.

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Teaching Assistant

• Reinforcement Learning (Grad)

UVA, Fall 2020

• Software Analysis and Applications (Grad)

UVA, Spring 2020

06/2017 - 08/2017

• Data Structures and Algorithms I (Undergrad)

UVA, Fall 2019

Conference Reviewer

 \bullet WSDM 2021, KDD 2021, AAAI 2022, AISTATS 2022

Journal Reviewer

• IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man and Cybernetics: Systems

Conference Volunteer

• KDD 2020

AWARDS

• Carlos and Esther Farrar Fellowship Awar	d UVA, 2021
• Academic Award for Grad Student	HIT, 2016
• Graduation with Distinction	HIT, 2016
\bullet Outstanding Undergrad Thesis Award	HIT, 2016
• National Scholarship for Undergrad	Ministry of Education, China, 2015
• CSC Scholarship for Undergrad Exchange Council, 2015	Program China Scholarship